# Khodar El-Helou

# SYSTEM PROGRAMMING & CYBER SECURITY

### **PROFILE**

Motivated and passionate 23-year-old Software Developer. I have a years' experience developing Web and Mobile Applications, and they can be viewed on my website and Github. My most recent experience consists of working for Western Sydney University. I have worked on two major systems HaWMAE and Coronavirus Monitoring. Both applications use Object-Oriented Programming and Data Structure Algorithms, to provide our client with the most well-structured and developed system.

#### CONTACT

PHONE: 0414 104 080

khodarelhelou@gmail.com

#### WEBSITE:

https://khodare.github.io/KhodarPortfolio.g ithub.io/Portfolio/

GITHUB: https://github.com/KhodarE

## LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/khodar-elhelou-20b281169/

# **STRENGTHS**

- Leadership
- Team orientated
- Strong attention to detail
- Working under pressure
- Continuous love to learn
- Communication skills
- Time and task management
- Big picture focus

### **EDUCATION**

## **Green Valley Primary and High School**

2003 - 2016

Performed and completed my Primary and Higher School education at Green Valley Islamic College. Graduated with an ATAR of 84.10

## **Western Sydney University**

2017 - 2020

Completed Bachelor of Computer Science at Kingswood Western Sydney University. Majored in System Programming and Cyber Security with an GPA score of 5.425

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## White Flame Creative - Graphics Designer (Work Experience) 10/2013 - 11/2013

Interpersonal skills among team members

- Time management
- Designed graphics for small businesses and private organisations

## Just 4 Kids Tutoring - Tutor (Casual)

01/2018 - 09/2019

- Review and mark student assignments and homework
- Educate students with new concepts in Math, English, Science, and Information Technology
- Taught students to respect their teachers and peers

# Western Sydney University - Software Developer (Part-time) 12/2019 - 11/2020

- Full Stack Web and Mobile Application Developer
- Worked on the HaWMAE website and Coronavirus Monitoring Mobile Application for iOS and Android
- Team leader and worked in strong team orientated group
- Worked very closely with the client, requesting changes and improvements to the system
- Weekly client meetings and daily group meetings
- Both applications were well received and are going to be used for research purposes starting 2021
- 12-month contract with the University to develop both systems
- Worked in a group of four and in which I was the leader and mentor

# **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

# Health and Well-being Mobile Application Evaluation (HaWMAE) Software Developer

- Front-end: Design the layout and functionality of the website using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Back-end: Connected website to server and linked the project to a database, so that data can be transmitted and received using PHP
- Developed the following functionalities: Login/register, request for account, CRUD projects and surveys, view data in bar/line/pie charts, download data to excel file, send email invitation and many more.
- Connected the website to servers and managed all the backend data being stored onto the database
- Leader within the team and compiled all other group members tasks into
- Daily group meetings whereby we filled out meeting agenda and minutes
- Assisted team members with tasks and fixed project errors
- Error checking to make sure system does not experience crashes or bugs

## **Project Management**

- Project Plan
- System Analysis and Design Report
- Test Scripts
- Entity Relationship Diagrams (ERD)
- System Flow Charts

- Project Proposal
- Handover Report
- Team Meetings
- Use cases
- Gantt Charts

## **Coronavirus Monitoring Mobile Application (iOS and Android)** Software Developer

- Front-end: Design the layout and functionality of the Coronavirus Monitoring Application both on XCode and Android Studios
- Back-end: Connected mobile application to server and Firebase to perform notifications and to transmit and retrieve information
- Developed the following functionalities: Login/register, Fill out account details, share location, show coronavirus hotspots on maps, send notification every 2-4 hours reminding clients to wear masks, sanitise and to wash their hands, frequently asked questions and clients can send questions and receive feedback.
- Connected the coronavirus application to firebase to manage notification and data management.
- Leader within the team and compiled all other group members tasks into one project
- Daily group meetings whereby we filled out meeting agenda and minutes
- Assisted team members with tasks and fixed project errors
- Error checking to make sure system does not experience crashes or bugs

# Project Management

- Project Plan
- System Analysis and Design Report
- Test Scripts
- Entity Relationship Diagrams (ERD)
- System Flow Charts

- Project Proposal
- Handover Report
- Team Meetings
- Use cases
- Gantt Charts

### **SKILLS**

# **Programming Languages**

- HTML
- ...4
- JavaScript
- CXML
- CSS
- Java
- C#Kotlin
- PHPC++
- Swift
- Visual Basic

## Frameworks and Technologies

- Visual Studio
- Android Studio
- React
- Git

- Laravel
- SwiftjQuery
- Vue.js
- ASP.NET
- Angular
- Node.js
- Github

# **Project Management Skills**

During my studies at Western Sydney University, I have learnt to perfect my Project Management and Report Writing Skills consisting of:

- Project Plan
- System Analysis and Design Report
- Test Scripts
- Entity Relationship Diagrams (ERD)
- System Flow Charts

- Project Proposal
- Handover Report
- Gantt Charts
- Use cases
- Screen Designs

## **REFERENCES**

References will be provided upon requests.